<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gunay Orbay, PHD</title>
    <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gunay Orbay, PHD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 20:50:42 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.gunayorbay.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Hugo</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/posts/welcome-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 20:50:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/posts/welcome-hugo/</guid>
      <description>After randomly learning about Hugo, the static webpage creator, I immediately wanted to give it a try as it resembled Jekyll quite a bit. To my surprise, I find Hugo to be much much easier to install in contrast to wrestling with ruby and gems. The difference is quite stark in the time that I spent to get the first page up and running.
The list of positives for me is quite short for now but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll have more than enough opinions about Hugo the more I use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of publications</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/posts/publication-list-is-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 16:14:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/posts/publication-list-is-online/</guid>
      <description>I am finally bringing back the list of publications, including abstracts, copy-paste bibtex citations, and more.
I intend to add more content besides just published work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 20:18:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone! This is my most recent attempt to perpare an easy-to-manage web space for myself.
After fruitless attempts with Wordpress, intermittent mysql problems, AWS EC2 setup difficulties, I am giving jekyll a try. It seems very straigtforward and easy IF you can manage to upgrade ruby to an acceptable version. My experience hasn&amp;rsquo;t been as smooth as advertised on a Macbook.
Welp! Till next time. - G</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Influence of Product Shape on Consumer Judgments Through Geometric Abstraction</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2015-01-01-jmd-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 20:18:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2015-01-01-jmd-0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Understanding and tailoring the visual elements of a developing product to evoke desired perceived qualities and a positive response from the consumer is a key challenge in industrial design. To date, computational approaches to assist this process have either relied on stiff geometric representations, or focused on superficial features that exclude often elusive shape characteristics. In this work, we aim to study the relationship between product geometry and consumers’ qualitative judgments through a visual decomposition and abstraction of existing products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pencil-like Sketch Rendering of 3D Scenes Using Trajectory Planning and Dynamic Tracking</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2014-03-16-jvlc-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 20:18:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2014-03-16-jvlc-0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Objective: We present a new non-photorealistic rendering method to render 3D scenes in the form of pencil-like sketches.
Methods: This work is based on the observation that the dynamic feedback mechanism involving the human visual system and the motor control of the hand collectively generates the visual characteristics unique to hand-drawn sketches. At the heart of our approach is a trajectory planning and tracking algorithm that generate the sketch in multiple layers using a dynamic pen model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape Design From Exemplar Sketches Using Graph-Based Sketch Analysis</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2012-01-01-jmd-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 20:18:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2012-01-01-jmd-0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We describe a new technique that works from a set of concept sketches to support the exploration and engineering of products. Our approach allows the capture and reuse of geometric shape information contained in concept sketches, as a means to generate solutions that can concurrently satisfy aesthetic and functional requirements. At the heart of our approach is a graph-based representation of sketches that allows the determination of topological and geometric similarities in the input sketches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch-Based Aesthetic Product Form Exploration from Existing Images Using Piecewise Clothoid Curves</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2012-01-01-jvlc-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 20:18:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2012-01-01-jvlc-0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present a new sketch-based product form exploration technique that works from images and sketches of existing products. At the heart of our approach, is a multi-stroke curve beautification method and a curve-based image deformation algorithm. The proposed approach converts groups of strokes into piecewise clothoid curves in order to produce visually pleasing shapes. The deformation diffusion algorithm then spatially distributes the user specified deformations through out the image to produce smooth transformations from the original image to the resulting image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch-based shape exploration using multiscale free-form surface editing</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2012-01-01-aiedam-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 20:18:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2012-01-01-aiedam-0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The hierarchical construction of solid models with current computer-aided design systems provides little support in creating and editing free-form surfaces commonly encountered in industrial design. In this work, we propose a new design exploration method that enables sketch-based editing of free-form surface geometries where specific modifications can be applied at different levels of detail. This multilevel detail approach allows the designer to work from existing models and make alterations at coarse and fine representations of the geometry, thereby providing increased conceptual flexibility during modeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch-Based Surface Design Using Malleable Curve Networks</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2012-01-01-cag-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 20:18:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2012-01-01-cag-0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present a new 3D surface modeling approach that enables curve-based creation and modification of smooth surfaces by sketching. The key feature of the proposed methods is a two-way communication between the user-designed curve networks and the generated surfaces. A user-drawn curve network serves as a control cage, from which a subdivision surface is generated. The subdivision surface is updated to match the curve network while minimizing the curvature variation throughout the surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautification of Design Sketches Using Trainable Stroke Clustering and Curve Fitting</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2010-01-01-tvcg-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 20:18:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/publications/2010-01-01-tvcg-0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We propose a new sketch parsing and beautification method that converts digitally created design sketches into beautified line drawings. Our system uses a trainable, sequential bottom-up and top-down stroke clustering method that learns how to parse input pen strokes into groups of strokes each representing a single curve, followed by point-cloud ordering that facilitates curve fitting and smoothing. This approach enables greater conceptual freedom during visual ideation activities by allowing designers to develop their sketches using multiple, casually drawn strokes without requiring them to indicate the separation between different stroke groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://www.gunayorbay.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gunayorbay.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an enthusiast of anything music, computer graphics, and arts. I hold mechanical engineering degrees from METU (BSc, MSc) and CMU (PhD) though my interests go beyond. I currently work at ANSYS Inc. as part of the Discovery Live team. You can reach me through Linkedin for professional inquiries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
